# RAHUL SHARMA

+91 9085289995 / 7999268061 ♦ Assam, IN

rsharma0374@gmail.com \leq www.linkedin.com/in/rahul0374/ \leq portfolio.r-sharma.in/ \leq r-sharma.in/

A motivated Java developer with 2.5+ years of experience in backend development seeking a challenging position where I can apply my Java programming skills and problem-solving abilities to contribute effectively towards building dynamic and resilient software solutions.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Senior Software Developer

Dec 2023 - Current Pune. IN

Lentra

- Led IDEARAS EStamping project development in Java. Developed cutting-edge solutions for effective electronic stamping operations. Utilized Java knowledge to design scalable and reliable systems for smooth project implementation and client satisfaction.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and maintain microservices-based applications using Java and Spring Framework, ensuring high performance and scalability.
- Strong working knowledge of Database Programming using and maintaining NoSQL(MongoDB) Triggers and Stored Procedures.
- Good developing and implementation skills in Core Java and J2EE technologies.
- Expertise in Programming with Core Java Concepts multithreading, collections, and asynchronous programming.
- Used AWS as a cloud platform leveraging its services and EC2. Setting up databases in AWS using S3 bucket and configuring instance backups to S3 bucket.
- Used BurpSuite tool for penetration testing of apis.

## Software Developer

Jan 2022 - Nov 2023

Pune, IN

- Have knowledge on NoSQL databases Mongo DB.
- Used Spring Web MVC framework.
- A result-driven, customer-focused and dedicated IT Professional with an approach to build quality application.
- Addressed and resolved VAPT (Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing) points promptly, enhancing the security posture of the applications.

#### **PROJECTS**

Lentra

**Privilege Club Membership.** Developed the "Privilege Club Membership" project in Java, integrating MongoDB database and APIs while incorporating encryption and decryption logic for enhanced data security.

**Pennant Migration** From LOS development to LMS integration. Streamlining data flow and improving interoperability between LOS and LMS. Implementing Java-based solutions for seamless communication and data exchange. Streamlining workflow and user experience.

**KYC.** Made contributions to the KYC (Know Your Customer) module, implementing strong data validation and verification procedures in order to improve compliance and reduce fraud.

**Face Authentication.** Implemented Face Authentication, adding advanced facial recognition technology to our apps, improving security and user experience.

CC bundling module. Played a pivotal role in the development and implementation of the CC bundling module, streamlining the distribution of credit cards to consumers, leading to a remarkable 30% growth in business operations and a substantial 20% reduction in processing time.

**Lead generation project.** Developed Java-based lead generation & in-store use cases such as self-service capabilities, DAP (Digital Asset Platforms) and HL BRE (Home Loan) to improve operational performance and customer engagement.

#### RESPONSIBILITIES

- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) as requirement gathering, data modeling, analysis, architecture design & development for the project.
- Involved in the discussions with business users, and the testing team to finalize the technical design documents and story point allocation for user stories.
- Designed Restful request and response to be used in the project.
- Used IntelliJ and Tomcat as web servers for deploying the application.
- Performed User Interface Design and coding using Java, and Spring framework.
- Helped the production support team to solve trouble reports.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills Java, Spring, Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, AWS, GIT, MicroSer-

vice, REST Service

Soft Skills Problem-solving, Attention to detail, Adaptability, Teamwork, Critical thinking,

and Continuous learning.

Development Tools IntelliJ IDEA, VS Code, NosqlBooster, Postman, BurpSuite, SonarQube.

Language Assamese, Bengali, English, Hindi.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering, LNCTE, Bhopal, MP

2016 - 2020

Intermediate Education, R.D Junior College, Digboi, AS

2013 - 2015

### ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Successfully completed the MongoDB Developer and Administrator course.
- Successfully completed Cybersecurity Awareness Program.
- Received the SPOT AWARD for outstanding effort and contribution in Client Delivery FY 22-23.
- Received the EXTRA MILLER AWARD for outstanding effort and contribution in Client Delivery FY 23-24.